Guide to the Carole Bisogni papers, 1989-2013.
Bisogni, Carole papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Carole Bisogni papers, 1989-2013.
23-5-4181
Bisogni, Carole Ayres,
1.3 cubic feet.
Research material and publications.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes biographical material, subject files, and publications pertaining to Bisogni's career at Cornell.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Bisogni joined the Division of Nutritional Sciences faculty in 1975 after her undergraduate (1970) and graduate studies (M.S. 1972, Ph.D. 1976) at Cornell in nutrition and food science. In 2007 she was named dean for academic affairs in the College of Human Ecology. As a researcher, Bisogni focused on understanding food choice; the personal, social, cultural and situational influences on human eating behaviors. With co-authors, she developed the Food Choice Process Model to assess the complex factors that shape our everyday food choices.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes biographical material, subject files, and publications pertaining to Bisogni's career at Cornell.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Bisogni, Carole Ayres, 1949-2014; Bisogni, Carole Ayres, 1949-2014; Cornell University -- Faculty.
Subjects:
World health.; Nutrition.; Food science.; Food habits.; Food preferences.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Biographical material, including vitae, 2000-2012 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Awards, 1989-2008 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Non-Confidential Tenure Notebook, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Non-Confidential Tenure Notebook, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Non-Confidential Tenure Notebook, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Thank yous, 1987-2000 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- MNS Degree in Community Nutrition, 2009-2011 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Academic Affairs Committee, 2003-2007 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Associate Director for Graduate Affairs - Responsibilities, 1990s (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Human Biology, Health and Society Major, 1995-2001 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Global Health Major, 2009-2013 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Biology and Society, 2011-2013 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Social Sciences Review Committee, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Nutrition, Food and Agriculture Major - Progress Report, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- DNS New Courses (Box 1, Folder 15)
- DNS- Memos and Correspondence, 2006-2010 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- PAM, 2006-2009 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Curriculum- Departments, 2010-2011 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Tenure Process and Teaching Evaluation, no date (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Admissions, 2007-2011 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Student Advisory Council, SUNY Teaching, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Educational Opportunity Program, 2008-2009 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Committee on Academic Status, 2004-2013 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Peer Partnership Program, 1998-2013 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Pre-freshman Summer Program, 2008-2013 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- FSAD, 2005-2013 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Human Ecology Building Communications- Video Board, 2010-2011 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Academic Affairs, 2011-2012 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Educational Policy Committee, 2010-2012 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Educational Policy Committee, 2008-2010 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Global and Public Health Sciences Major, 2009-2013 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Global Education, 2012-2013 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Global Health, 2007-2008 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Exchange Agreements, 2008-2011 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Exchange Agreements, 2010-2013 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Leadership, 2009-2012 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Leadership, 2011-2012 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- 3 Disks - Understanding Chemical Exposure- by Bisogni, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Article - "The Impact of Technology" by Bisogni and Christine Olson, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 6)